Guide to the Western Americana Card Photograph File
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Identified Photographers, circa 1851-1965; Series I; 672
  - Brown, Ernest
    - View from the Cliff House, Edmonton, Alberta, 1926-1927; 12.5 x 20.1 cm, unmounted (Box 2)
      Blindstamp imprint: "Copyright Ernest Brown Edmonton Alta. Can."
  - Brush, James A.
    Photographer in Minneapolis, Minnesota
    - Self-portrait of James A. Brush, 1889; 14.0 x 9.7 cm on mount 16.6 x 10.7 cm (Box 2)
  - Buchtel, Joseph (1830-1916)
    - Studio portrait of a man, circa 1866-1872; 9.1 x 5.7 cm, on mount 10.0 x 6.2 cm (Box 2)
  - Buck, Isaac N. (born 1859)
    Photographer in Paola, Kansas
    - Looking west towards the square in Paola, Kansas, circa 1880-1889; 10.0 x 14.0 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.5 cm (Box 2)
  - Budd, James (born 1865)
    Photographer in Devils Lake, North Dakota
    - Two panorama views of an unidentified town, possibly Devil's Lake, North Dakota, circa 1875-1880; 5.0 x 19.8 cm and 6.6 x 20.0 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.3 cm (Box 2)
  - Buehman & Company
    Photography studio in Tucson, Arizona
    - Copy photograph of a painting of Mission San Xavier del Bac, Tucson, Arizona, 1883; 12.8 x 19.9 cm on mount 13.6 x 21.6 cm (Box 2)
  - Buehman, Henry H. (1851-1912)
    Photographer in Tucson, Arizona
    - Studio portrait of a young Pima Indian woman, circa 1875-1880; 14.2 x 10.0 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 2)
    - Studio portrait of Chapo, an Apache Indian man, posed standing with a rifle, circa 1875-1880; 14.2 x 9.9 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.7 cm (Box 2)
      Inscribed in negative: Chapo, Apache
    - Studio portrait of an Apache Indian man posed standing with a rifle, circa 1875-1880; 14.2 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.7 cm (Box 2)
      Inscribed in negative: War dance
    - Giant cactus near Tucson, Arizona, circa 1875-1880; 14.4 x 10.0 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 2)
    - Copy photograph of an Apache Indian child in a cradleboard, circa 1875-1880; 14.0 x 10.0 cm on mount 16.4 x 10.8 cm (Box 2)
  - Buell, Oliver B. (1844-1910)
    Photographer in Montreal, Quebec
    - Studio portrait of Chief Crowfoot (1830-1890), also known as Sapomaxiko, 1885; 13.8 x 10.2 cm on mount 16.4 x 10.8 cm (Box 2)
      Inscribed on the negative, "Crowfoot. Copyright Secured, 1885. Prof. Buell,"
      Ink inscription on the verso: "Chef des Pied-Noirs Nord-Ouest. Visite a Montreal 26 Sept 1886. Bazar de la Cathedrale"
  - Burge, Joseph C. (1839-1897)
    Photographer in Kingston, New Mexico
    - Gallup, New Mexico, 1885-1891; 12 x 19.1 cm on mount 12.6 x 20.3 cm (Box 2)
      Purchased from Michael Vinson on the William Robertson Coe Fund No. 3, 2012
    - Zuni Pueblo, New Mexico, 1885-1891; 11.5 x 18.8 cm on mount 12.6 x 20.3 cm (Box 2)
  - Burgess
    - View of American Indians butchering cattle near a corral, probably during a meat distribution on a reservation, circa 1895; 12.5 x 20.1 cm on mount 13.2 x 21.5 cm (Box 2)
  - Burns Photo Company
    Photography studio in Lewiston, Idaho; operated by Robert Burns and William J. Burns
    - Dedication of Lapwai Mission site marker, 1924 Jun; 12.9 x 18.1 cm, unmounted (Box 2)
    - Dedication of Lapwai Mission site, 1924 Jun; 12.9 x 18.1 cm, unmounted (Box 2)
  - Butterfield & Ralston
    Photography studio in Sioux Falls, South Dakota; operated by Leroy T. Butterfield (born 1852) and Ralston
    - Studio portrait of White Moon and Rock Road, Cheyenne Indian scouts, circa 1891; 14.1 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.4 x 10.8 cm (Box 2)
  - Butterfield, Leroy T. (born 1852)
    Photographer in Sioux Falls, South Dakota
    - Studio portraits of Plenty Horses
      Plenty Horses, also known as Senika-Wakan-Ota (circa 1879-1933), a Brulé Dakota Indian accused of killing Lieutenant Edward H. Casey near the Pine Ridge Agency, South Dakota, on January 7, 1891
      - Studio portrait of Plenty Horses, 1891; 14.0 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.4 x 10.8 cm (Box 2)
      - Studio portrait of Plenty Horses with his father, Living Bear, and Phillip H. Wells, 1891; 14.0 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.4 x 10.8 cm (Box 2)
      - Studio portrait of Plenty Horses with his father, Living Bear, and Chris Mathison, 1891; 14.0 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.4 x 10.8 cm (Box 2)
  - Byram, W. B.
    Photographer in Pasadena and Lamanda Park, California
    - View on top of the Muir Glacier, Alaska, circa 1885-1900; 11.5 x 19.5 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 2)
    - House and yard, circa 1885-1900; 11.2 x 20.0 cm on mount 13.2 x 21.5 cm (Box 2)
    - View on the Indian River, Sitka, Alaska, circa 1885-1900; 11.5 x 19.5 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 2)
    - Suspension bridge across Indian River, Sitka, Alaska, circa 1885-1900; 11.5 x 19.5 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 2)
    - A snow cave near Sitka, Alaska, circa 1885-1900; 11.6 x 19.5 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 2)
  - California Art Gallery
    Photography studio in Santa Rosa, California
    - Rabbit drive in Tulare County, California, circa 1891; 10.3 x 15.8 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.4 cm (Box 2)
      Gift of Michael Vinson, 2013
      Image number 20 in series, rare Views of California
      Descriptive text on recto: Where over 600 rabbits were killed; no dogs or guns were allowed, a club being the only weapon used
  - Cannon, Marsena (1812-1900)
    Photographer in Salt Lake City, Utah
    - Studio portrait of Brigham Young (1801-1877), circa 1851-1852; 24.0 x 19.5 cm, unmounted (Box 2)
      Retouched enlargement of an original image
  - Carbutt, John (1832-1905)
    Photographer in Chicago, Illinois
    Images originally sold by Sold by Martin's Art Gallery, 264 Third, Saint Paul, Minnesota
    - Men and women on the shore of White Bear Lake, Minnesota, 1866-1869; 5.3 x 8.6 cm on mount 6.2 x 10.1 cm (Box 3)
    - Men and women with boats on the shore of White Bear Lake, Minnesota, 1866-1869; 5.3 x 8.6 cm on mount 6.2 x 10.1 cm (Box 3)
    - Two women on the shore of White Bear Lake, Minnesota, 1866-1869; 5.3 x 8.6 cm on mount 6.2 x 10.1 cm (Box 3)
    - A woman seated on the shore of White Bear Lake, Minnesota, 1866-1869; 5.3 x 8.6 cm on mount 6.2 x 10.1 cm (Box 3)
    - A man and two women seated on the shore of White Bear Lake, Minnesota, 1866-1869; 5.3 x 8.6 cm on mount 6.2 x 10.1 cm (Box 3)
    - Men and women with a tree-swing on the shore of White Bear Lake, Minnesota, 1866-1869; 5.3 x 8.6 cm on mount 6.2 x 10.1 cm (Box 3)
  - Carpenter, A. C. (born 1847)
    Photographer in Tacoma, Washington
    - Studio portrait of Paul Schulge, Northern Pacific Railroad Land Agent, circa 1895; 14.0 x 10.0 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.9 cm (Box 3)
  - Carter, Charles William (1832-1918)
    - Copy photograph of lithograph, H. R. Robinson, "The Extermination of the Latter Day Saints from the State of Missouri in the Fall of 1838", circa 1875-1890; 10.5 x 14.3 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.5 cm (Box 3)
  - Cassillir, C. W.
    Photographer in Saint Louis, Missouri
    - Saint Louis street scene with globe decoration for the Louisiana Purchase Exposition, 1904 Apr-Dec; 14.2 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 3)
      Manuscript inscription on verso: "St. Louis Fair, 1904"
  - Chapman, Robert M.
    - Plains of the Upper Missouri River, showing men, horses and mules crossing the plains, circa 1885-1910; 9.9 x 12.4 cm, unmounted (Box 3)
      Printed on paperboard
  - Chase, Dana B.
    Photographer in Santa Fe, New Mexico, and Trinidad, Colorado
    - Group of Mexican dancers seated, circa 1870-1879; 11.0 x 18.2 cm on mount 13.4 x 21.7 cm (Box 3)
    - Taos Pueblo on the day of the San Geronimo Feast, circa 1870-1879; 11.0 x 18.2 cm on mount 13.4 x 21.7 cm (Box 3)
      Verso has a typescript advertisement for the Denver and Rio Grande Railroad
    - View of an unidentified hotel, circa 1880-1889; 9.9 x 15.8 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.5 cm (Box 3)
      Printed text of "Los Burros" superimposed over the image
    - Unidentified hotel, circa 1880-1889; 11.1 x 18.1 cm on mount 12.6 x 20.3 cm (Box 3)
  - Cherry, Edgar (1848-1930)
    Photographer in Santa Rosa, California
    - Logging train, with a log 17 feet in diameter, circa 1880; 10.4 x 15.7 cm on mount 13.2 x 21.7 cm (Box 3)
      Purchased from William Reese Co. on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2013
      Forms part of series, In the Redwoods, at Guerneville, near Santa Rosa, Sonoma County, California
      Image number 4
  - Chesley, G. W. (1829-1912)
    Photographer in Owatonna, Minnesota
    - View of a wooden church near Owatonna, Minnesota, circa 1869-1870; 5.6 x 8.7 cm on mount 6.2 x 10.1 cm (Box 3)
  - Chile's Deco Company
    Photography studio in Austin, Texas
    - Zier-Phillips Furniture Company store, Austin, Texas, circa 1900-1910; 14.0 x 8.2 cm on mount 18.7 x 13.0 cm (Box 3)
    - Past Deep Eddy, which shows a young girl on the bank of a shallow gulch, circa 1900-1910; 7.6 x 13.5 cm on mount 12.9 x 18.7 cm (Box 3)
  - Choate, John N. (1848-1902)
    Photographer in Carlisle, Pennsylvania
    - Studio portrait of Tom Torlino, a Navajo Indian as he appeared upon his arrival at the United States Indian School in Carlisle, Pennsylvania, circa 1882; 20.2 x 12.4 cm on mount 21.6 x 13.5 cm (Box 3)
  - Churchill, John
    Photographer in Hastings, Nebraska
    - Sod House of Myron W. Hickok (or Hickock) in Webster, Nebraska, circa 1880; 9.8 x 13.5 cm on mount 10.6 x 16.4 cm (Box 3)
  - Churchill, R. E.
    Photographer in Albany, New York
    - Studio portrait of LeBaron Bradford Prince (1840-1922), circa 1868-1877; 8.9 x 5.3 cm on mount 10.0 x 6.1 cm (Box 3)
      LeBaron Bradford Prince (1840-1922) was a delegate to Republican National Convention from New York in 1868; a member of New York State Assembly, 1870-1874; a member of New York State Senate, 1876-1877; and a justice of the New Mexico Territorial Supreme Court, 1878-1882
  - Clark, John C.
    Photographer in La Grande, Oregon
    - View of La Grande, Oregon, 1889-1891; 11.0 x 19.9 cm on mount 13.4 x 21.5 cm (Box 3)
  - Clatworthy, Fred Payne (1875-1953)
    Photographer in Estes Park, Colorado
    - Fall River Road in Rocky Mountain National Park, Colorado, circa 1925-1935; 17.9 x 24.8 cm, unmounted (Box 3)
  - Clinton, J. L.
    Photographer in Colorado Springs, Colorado
    - Pillars of Hercules, South Cheyenne Canyon, Colorado, circa 1888-1896; 19.2 x 11.2 cm on mount 20.3 x 12.7 cm (Box 3)
  - Collier, Charles T.
    Photographer in Riverside, California
    - Magnolia Avenue, Riverside, California, 1886-1888; 11.4 x 19.9 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.5 cm (Box 3)
    - Glenwood Home, Riverside, California, 1886-1888; 11.7 x 19.9 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.4 cm (Box 3)
  - Collier, Joseph M. (1836-1910)
    Photographer in Central City, Colorado
    - View of Central City, Colorado, circa 1871-1878; 14.0 x 9.7 cm on mount 16.6 x 10.8 cm (Box 3)
      Typescript on verso: "Central City is the oldest mining town in Colorado. It is situated in the heart of the mining region, is the country seat of Gilpin County, has a population of about five thousand people, and has an elevation of from 8,000 to 8,900 feet above the level of the sea. It is midway between Black Hawk and Nevada, forming with them a continuous town that is connected by rail with the K. P. and U. P. Railways."
    - View of a bridge at Boulder, Colorado, circa 1871-1878; 13.5 x 9.5 cm on mount 16.6 x 10.7 cm (Box 3)
      Typescript on verso: "From Boulder City, looking southwest. Boulder City, from which this view is taken, is situated near the base of the mountains at an elevation of 5,536 feet above the sea, in the heart of one of the best agricultural regions of Colorado, watered by the beautiful crystal waters of the Boulder, whose banks are fringed with luxuriant foliage. It has excellent public school buildings, churches, etc., and two railroads connecting it with the east - the Boulder Valley and Colorado Central. Cliffs of sandstone are seen in the back-ground."
  - Commercial View Company
    Photography studio in Spokane, Washington
    - Steamer Idaho on the St. Joe River, circa 1903-1910; 20.6 x 25.4 cm, unmounted (Box 3)
  - Conaway, B. F.
    Photographer in Santa Ana, California
    - View in Mr. Hall's front yard, Santa Ana, California, circa 1880-1890; 11.3 x 18.7 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.5 cm (Box 3)
    - View on North Main Street, Santa Ana, California, circa 1880-1890; 10.9 x 19.9 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 3)
    - A rosebush in bloom, circa 1894; 10.9 x 19.9 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 3)
  - Conaway, B. F.
    - Pumpkin patch, circa 1894; 10.8 x 17.9 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.5 cm (Box 3)
    - Fourth Street, Santa Ana, California, circa 1894; 10.9 x 18.9 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 3)
  - Cooper, S. H.
    - Outdoor portrait of a group of adults and children, circa 188501890; 10.9 x 18.8 cm on mount 13.8 x 20.4 cm (Box 3)
  - Cottage Gallery
    Photography studio in Saint Joseph, Missouri
    - Photograph of a large bull and his owner, identified as Prince of the Plaines (sic), circa 1890; 9.8 x 14 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.5 cm (Box 3)
      Title in inscription in print continues: "Weight 4475, Height 19 1/2 Hands, Length 17 ft., R. Hoffman, Prop"
  - Crockwell, James H., 1855-1940
    Photographer in Salt Lake City, Utah, and Virginia City, Nevada
    - View of Virginia City, Nevada, circa 1886-1888; 12.3 x 20.3 cm on mount 13.1 x 21.2 cm (Box 3)
  - Cross, William R.
    Photographer in Fort Randall, Dakota Territory
    - Studio portrait of White Bird (circa 1841-1896), also known as Zintkala Ska, an Oglala Indian man and member of the Tapisleca (Spleen) Band, circa 1878; 2 photographic prints: 17.2 x 10.1 cm on mount 21.5 x 13.4 cm, and 14.1 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.7 x 11.0 cm (Box 3)
    - View over the Rosebud Agency, South Dakota, circa 1878-1885; 11.6 x 19.4 cm on mount 13.4 x 21.5 cm (Box 3)
      Image number 446
    - Studio portrait of One Bull, a Dakota Indian man, 1882; 15.2 x 10.1 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 3)
      Print number 7
    - Studio portrait of Sitting Bull, also known as Taton Kaiyotonka, a Dakota Indian man, 1882; 15.2 x 10.1 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 3)
      Print number 1
      Typescript list of available titles printed on verso, in addition to: "Address, Bailey, Dix, & Mead, Fort Randall, D. T." and "This noted Chief, With his band of Uncapapa Sioux Indians, now prisoners of war at Fort Randall, D. T., is 43 years of age; Weight 200 pounds; Height, 5 ft., 9 in. Has had over 100 engagements with their natural enemies, the Crows, of which he proudly boasts, but is too shrewd to acknowledge to having killed any whites. He has had 9 wives. The two now living with him appear with descriptions in Nos. 5, 11, and 20. Has had one child by each of his first 6 wives."
    - Studio portrait of Steps, a Nez Perce Indian man, 1882; 15.2 x 10.1 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 3)
      Print number 3
      Title on verso of cabinet card with photographer's information: "Address, Bailey, Dix & Mead, Fort Randall, D. T.," list of other subjects and description: "A Nes (sic) Perce Indian, who escaped from his band, while surrounded in the bad lands of Nebraska, by Gen'l Miles, in 1878. He then joined Sitting Bull's band of Uncapapa Sioux Indians in the British possessions and has followed their fortunes ever since. He lost his feet above the ankles, also his right hand by being frozen, having been caught in one of the severe snow storms, 21 years ago."
    - Bald Mountain Views, Nevada Gulch and Gold Mining Interests, including the Fremont, Elkhorn, and Missouri Valley Railway, circa 1889; 16.8 x 21.7 cm on mount 20.3 x 25.8 cm (Box 3)
    - View of Hot Springs, South Dakota, including Hotel Evans, Minnekahta Block, Gillespie Hotel, and Battle Mountain, circa 1892; 16.7 x 24.6 cm on mount 17.5 x 25 cm (Box 3)
      Purchased from Sindell and Company on the Winlock William Miller, Jr. Memorial Fund, 2010
    - View of men posed in front of the Hotel Evans under construction in Hot Springs, South Dakota, circa 1892; 16.3 x 23 cm on mount 17.5 x 25 cm (Box 3)
      Existence and Location of Copies
  - Culver, William H. (1853-1937)
    Photographer in Maiden, Montana
    - Maiden Concert Band on a main street of Maiden, Montana, on New Year's Day, circa 1888-1890; 13.9 x 21.4 cm on mount 13.9 x 21.4 cm (Box 3)
  - Cummings, Everett G.
    - Studio portrait of Nez Perce Indian woman with baby, 1900-1902; 13.8 x 9.9 cm on mount 16.8 x 11 cm (Box 3)
    - Studio portrait of Nez Perce Indian woman and boy, 1900-1902; 14 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.4 x 10.2 cm (Box 3)
    - Studio portrait of Gilbert Minthorn (born 1875), an Umatilla Indian man, 1900-1902; 13.8 x 9.9 cm on mount 16.8 x 11.1 cm (Box 3)
    - Studio portrait of Nez Perce Indian girl, 1900-1902; 13.9 x 9.9 cm on mount 16.8 x 11.1 cm (Box 3)
  - Dalgleish, George
    Photographer in Georgetown, Colorado
    - View of Green Lake, Colorado, circa 1888; 11.4 x 17.8 cm on mount 12.6 x 20.3 cm (Box 3)
      Embossed with a seal from an indecipherable company, 1888
      Mount missing its upper left corner
      Purchased from Thomas C. Klopp on the Arthur Corbitt Hoskins Memorial Fund, 2013
  - Dally, Frederick (1838-1914)
    - Entrance to a First Nations home with four American Indians and a statue in the doorway, circa 1866-1870; 9.4 x 5.9 cm on mount 10.2 x 6.1 cm (Box 3)
      Purchased from the William Reese Company (Cowan's sale, 2009 December 9, lot 236) on the Walter McClintock Memorial Fund for Western Americana, 2010
    - Studio portrait of a Sheeshat Indian man, circa 1866-1870; 9 x 5.5 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.3 cm (Box 3)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian man, circa 1866-1870; 8.6 x 5.5 cm on mount 10.2 x 6.1 cm (Box 3)
  - Dames & Dorsez
    Photography studio in Oakland, California; partnership of William W. Dames (born 1842) and Fernando H. Dorsez (born 1860)
    - Studio portrait of John L. Davie (1850-1934), circa 1888-1901; 20.0 x 13.8 cm on mount 25.4 x 17.9 cm (Box 3)
      Davie was a mayor of Oakland, California (1895-1897 and 1915-1831) and author of My Own Story(1931)
  - Davidson Brothers
    Photographers in Portland, Oregon; partnership of Isaac Grundy Davidson and John S. Davidson
    - Studio portrait of Cushing Eels (1810-1893), 1878-1879; 8.9 x 6.0 cm on mount 10.0 x 6.3 cm (Box 3)
  - Davidson, Isaac Grundy (1884-1891)
    - Train in East Portland, Oregon, 1883; 12.2 x 20.9 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.4 cm (Box 4)
    - Decapod locomotive pushing railroad ties during construction of the Stampede Tunnel, Washington, 1887; 11.6 x 20.7 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.4 cm (Box 4)
    - Rooster Rock, Columbia River, Washington, from Oregon Railway and Navigation Company Railroad, circa 1878-1888; 11.6 x 19.9 cm, unmounted (Box 4)
    - Copy photograph of a painting of Mount Hood, Oregon, from Portland distant, circa 1888; 11.7 x 20.0 cm on paper mount 12.8 x 20.2 cm (Box 4)
  - Davis, Robert M.
    Photographer in Denver, Colorado
    - Leadville, Colorado from Capitol Hill, circa 1887; 10.8 x 16.8 cm on mount 11.5 x 17.9 cm (Box 4)
    - Group portrait of members of the Denver Chamber of Commerce, circa 1887; 11.2 x 17.0 cm on mount 11.4 x 17.8 cm (Box 4)
    - Black Canyon, Colorado, circa 1887; 17.0 x 10.7 cm on mount 17.8 x 11.4 cm (Box 4)
    - Black Canyon, Colorado, circa 1887; 17.0 x 11.1 cm on mount 17.8 x 11.4 cm (Box 4)
  - Davis, W. A.
    Photographer in Manitou Springs, Colorado
    - Rainbow Falls, Ute Pass, Colorado, circa 1888; 19.5 x 11.6 cm on mount 20.4 x 12.7 cm (Box 4)
      Image number 1201
    - Balanced Rock, Garden of the Gods, Colorado, circa 1888; 19.2 x 11.7 cm on mount 20.3 x 12.7 cm (Box 4)
      Halftone image of Balanced Rock affixed to the verso
    - Gateway to Garden of the Gods, Colorado, circa 1888; 11.4 x 19.3 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.2 cm (Box 4)
      Image number 1431
    - The Palisades, Gunnison River, Colorado, circa 1880-1890; 19 x 11.4 cm on mount 20.3 x 12.7 cm (Box 4)
      Image number 651
    - Copy photograph of the Three Graces, Garden of the Gods, Colorado, circa 1880-1890; 18.8 x 11.1 cm on mount 20.2 x 12.5 cm (Box 4)
      Photograph originally created by William Henry Jackson
  - Day, Victor
    Photographer in Mansfield, Ohio
    - Studio portrait of Ernest James Wessen (1887-1974), proprietor of the Midland Rare Book Company, circa 1950; 25.4 x 20.7 cm, unmounted (Box 4)
  - Dean, Frank E.
    Photographer in Gunnison, Colorado
    - Augusta Mine and Miners, Poverty Gulch, Colorado, circa 1883-1889; 11.1 x 18.4 cm on mount 12.8 x 20.4 cm (Box 4)
      Manuscript inscriptions on verso in Swedish
    - Gillett's Office, Pittsburg, Colorado, Augusta Mountain in the distance, circa 1883-1889; 11.7 x 18.8 cm on mount 12.8 x 20.3 cm (Box 4)
    - Augusta Falls of the Slate Creek, Augusta Mountain in distance, circa 1883-1889; 11.5 x 18.8 cm on mount 12.6 x 20.3 cm (Box 4)
    - Burrow Pack Train for Augusta Mine, Poverty Gulch, Colorado, circa 1883-1889; 10.1 x 19.2 cm on mount 12.8 x 20.3 cm (Box 4)
  - Dellenbaugh, Frederick Samuel (1853-1935), collector
    Frederick Samuel Dellenbaugh was an American explorer. From 1871 to 1873, he served as an artist and assistant topographer with the second expedition led by John Wesley Powell down the Colorado River. In 1899, he joined an expedition to Alaska and Siberia financed by Edward Henry Harriman. He served as librarian of the American Geographical Society (1909-1911) and a fellow of the American Ethnological Society.
    - Studio portrait of Almon Harris Thompson (1839-1906), circa 1872; 9.6 x 6.3 cm, unmounted tintype (Box 4)
      Thompson was the chief assistant of John Wesley Powell during expeditions of the Colorado River and the surrounding plateau country from1870 to 1878, a geographer with the United States Geological Survey (1882-1906), and uncle of Frederick Samuel Dellenbaugh
    - View of Walpi, First Mesa, Hopi, Arizona, circa 1884; 12.7 x 17.8 cm on mount 19.9 x 25.0 cm (Box 4)
    - Antelope Valley, Nevada, looking south, circa 1900; 13.0 x 20.7 cm, unmounted (Box 4)
    - Navajo Indian women carding wool, circa 1900; 11.8 x 16.3 cm on mount 20.4 x 25.5 cm (Box 4)
      Manuscript on verso about Navajo weaving, signed "F. S. D"
    - Navajo Indian women weaving wool, circa 1900; 11.8 x 16.3 cm on mount 20.4 x 25.5 cm (Box 4)
  - Delong, W. W.
    Photographer in Sioux City, Iowa
    - Corn Palace in Sioux City, Iowa, 1887; 9.9 x 14.1 cm on mount 11.4 x 17.8 cm (Box 4)
  - Disher, W. E.
    Photographer in Saint Edward, Nebraska
    - Lillian Lounderman at Saint Edward, Nebraska, circa 1885; 9.3 x 11.0 cm on mount 10.8 x 13.3 cm (Box 4)
    - James O. Disher's farm at Saint Edward, Nebraska, circa 1885; 12.2 x 9.8 cm on mount 13.3 x 10.8 cm (Box 4)
    - On the millrace at Saint Edward, Nebraska, circa 1885; 11.8 x 9.3 cm on mount 13.3 x 10.8 cm (Box 4)
  - Dobbs, Beverly Bennett
    Photographer in Bellingham, Washington
    - Wharf in Nome, Alaska, circa 1904-1907; 19.7 x 24.4 cm on mount 23.9 x 28.4 cm (Box 4)
  - Dore, William
    Photographer in Butte, Montana
    - Studio portrait of a man, circa 1900; 14.9 x 7.6 cm on mount 18.3 x 10.1 cm (Box 4)
  - Dossetter, Edward
    Edward Dossetter was a photographer abopard the H.M.S. Rocket during its tour of Indian villages in British Columbia in 1881
    - Large group of Kwakiutl Indians at Tsanwati, Knight's Inlet, with houses and totem poles, 1881; 14.5 x 20.2 cm on mount 15.3 x 22.9 cm (Box 4)
      Purchased from Stephen C. Lunsford on the Winlock William Miller, Jr. Memorial Fund, 2010
    - View of Fort Simpson, including the Methodist mission, 1881; 14.1 x 20.5 cm on mount 15.4 x 23.9 cm (Box 4)
    - Elderly Haida woman with a labret piercing making a hat at Yan, Haida Gwaii, 1881; 13.2 x 13.2 cm on mount 14.3 x 13.2 cm (Box 4)
  - Dounley
    Photographer in San Diego, California
    - Group of American Indian women in San Diego County aged from 80 to 128 years, 1892 Sep 28-30; 10.7 x 18.3 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 4)